Finding Aid for Charles A. Kent papers, 1877 and 1898
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Charles A. Kent papers 1877 and 1898
Kent, Charles A. (Charles Artemas),1835-1917.
13 items in 1 folder
851595 Aa/1
Professor of law at University of Michigan. Papers include a report of his faculty activities for the period 1876-1877, and correspondence relating to his study of Michigan jurist, Thomas M. Cooley, including letters from James B. Angell, Henry Carter Adams, Charles Horton Cooley, Norman Geddes and Benjamin L. Baxter.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Door no. 1333
The collection is open to research.
Charles Artemas Kent was born in Hopkinton, New York, Oct. 11, 1835, the son of Artemas and Sarah (Weed) Kent. He received a A.B. from the University of Vermont in 1856 and studied at Andover Theological Seminary, 1857-1859. Kent was admitted to the Michigan Bar in 1960 began practicing law in Detroit. Kent joined the Law School faculty in 1868. He had been a student in the law office of Professor Charles I. Walker before joining the faculty as the Fletcher Professor of Law. The position named for Judge Fletcher of Massachusetts, who had made a valuable contribution to the Law Library. Kent succeeded Thomas M. Cooley as dean of the Law School in 1883 and held the position until 1886. Kent died May 17, 1917.
The Charles A. Kent papers consist of a report of his faculty activities for the period 1876-1877, and correspondence relating to his study of Michigan jurist, Thomas M. Cooley, including letters from James B. Angell, Henry Carter Adams, Charles Horton Cooley, Norman Geddes and Benjamin L. Baxter.
Subjects:
Cooley, Thomas McIntyre, 1824-1898.; University of Michigan--Faculty.; University of Michigan. Dept. of Law.
Contributors:
Adams, Henry Carter, 1851-1921.; Angell, James Burrill, 1829-1916.; Baxter, Benjamin Levi, 1815-1902.; Cooley, Charles Horton, 1864-1929.; Geddes, Norman, b. 1823.
- Papers
  - Report on faculty duties, 1876/77 (Folder 1)
  - Correspondence relating to Judge Thomas M. Cooley
    - From Charles H. Cooley, October 28, 1898
    - From Charles H Cooley, November 2, 1898
    - From Benjamin Levi Baxter, November 2, 1898
    - From B.F. Graves, November 2, 1898
    - From James E. Callahan, November 4, 1898
    - From J. W. Champlin, November 9, 1898
    - From W. J. Cocker, November 10, 1898
    - From Norma n A. Geddes, November 14, 1898, 2 items
    - From J. H. Loomis, November 18, 1898
    - From Norman A. Geddes, November 19, 1898
    - From Henry Carter Adams, November 23, 1898
    - From Charles Horton Cooley, December 12, 1898
    - From James B. Angell, December 28, 1898
Related Material
Copies of several essays and lectures by Charles A. Kent are cataloged separately at the Bentley Historical Library, including:
Memorial Address on Thomas McIntyre Cooley, Feb. 26, 1899 [call no. DB 2 C774 M624]
The Law as a Means of Justice, closing Address Delivered to the Graduating Law Class of the U of M, 1881 [call no. J 17 .K37 L415]
Direct Government by the People, An essay. [call no. J 17 .K37]
The Truth, An essay. [call no. J 17 .K37]